

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Experience & expertise in Global Delivery, Consulting, Technology and Transformation services with technologies Cloud, DevOps, Agile, Java and .NET



Current Designation: Cloud & DevOps Lead

Total Experience: 21 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Capgemini Technology Services India Ltd

Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Mumbai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance Role: Program Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: consulting lead, devops, agile, delivery management, program management, director, people

management, Practice Management

Verified : L Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

Summary

- Seasoned Professional in Practice/ COE Set-up and Development, Delivery Leadership, Consulting and team management. 20+ Years of experience in Consulting, Delivery, Technology, Transformation and Presales

- Key Activities at current role includes DevOps COE business development, Develop solutions, Delivery, Build accelerators and demo to customers, Pre-sales support, Customer interactions and Proposal preparation

Good Experience in DevOps Architecture, Agile, Cloud Solutions (AWS & Azure), Customer Experience Management, Pre-Sales Support, Global Delivery, CMM, PMO, Quality Audit, Program Management, Scrum Master, Competency Development, People Management

 Profession Experience: Associated with Capgemini as DevOps COE Lead for more than 1.5 years; Worked in EMC, Infosys & TCS, prior to Capgemini

Worked in various domains for global customers, Financial Services, Insurance, Govt, Healthcare & MFG

- Managing team of 100 associates being part of COE

Work Experience

- Capgemini Technology Services India Ltd as Cloud & DevOps Lead Sep 2018 to Till Date
 - Presently working for US based financial services client for setting up of AWS Cloud and setting up of DevOps Pipeline for AEM Application Development and Testing activities.
- Worked on setting up DevOps COE and bring-up the competency for FS BU. DevOps COE Competency build, Solution offerings, Pre-sales Support, Solutions and Accelerators, Customer Demo, Customer Experience management
- Worked for multiple Financial Services clients for DevOps, Agile and Cloud Assessment, Development Implementation and Transformation.
- $\quad \hbox{Worked on Technologies: AWS Cloud, Azure DevOps, DevOps Tools, Agile, Scrum, Cloud transformation} \\$
- Roles Played: Cloud and DevOps Architect, Cloud & DevOps Consultant, Agile & DevOps Transformation Lead, DevOps Maturity Assessment & Pre-Sales Support
- EMC Software and Services India Pvt Ltd as Application Modernization Practice Lead Oct 2009 to Oct 2017
 - Application Modernization Lead (Cloud, Agile & DevOps, Aug 2013 Oct 2017): Consulting, DevOps and Agile Transformation, Cloud Solutions; Pre-sales Support; Hiring, Partner Ecosystem
- Program Delivery Lead (Mcrosoft Stack and Java Applications, Oct 2009 Aug 2013): Delivery, Program Management; Customer Interaction; Business Growth; Pre-sales Support; Hiring; Vendor Management
- Infosys Technologies as Technical Project Manager/ Program Manager Aug 2007 to Apr 2009

Technical Project Manager/ Program Manager: Technical Architecture, Project/ Program Management; Worked with Telecom customers for development of portal using .NET and SharePoint Project management for several projects for USA based Teleco customer, on SharePoint, SQL Server.

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

- Active participation into Proposal preparation, estimation, POC, Proposal demo to prospective customers
- Program management of multiple projects including Balanced scorecard, Risk assessment framework, revenue tracker etc., within MFG BU. Complete life cycle of these projects was managed effectively
- Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) as Lead Architect/ Technical PM Oct 2000 to Aug 2007

Development, Technical Architecture; Project Management; PMO; Internal Quality Auditor; CMM Process; Project Estimation; Team Management; VB; ASP; .NET; Java; Architect applications on .NET and SharePoint, Development and Testing. Demo to customers

Vibrant & Mittsoft Technologies as Technical Lead, Analyst Jun 1997 to Oct 2000

Application Design, development, Testing, System Analysis and Design; VB; ASP; SQL Server, MS Access

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Maths) from Nagarjuna University in 1993 PG: MCA (Computers) from Andhra University in 1997

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Certified Scrum Master

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
DevOps, Agile (Sprint), Docker	
Jenkins, Chef, Kubernetes	
Kanban, Git, Maven, JUnit, JMeter	
SonarQube	
Selenium, Puppet, Nagios	
JIRA, Edipse, Shift left	
Java, Python, XML, JSON	
RESTful Web Services, SOAP	
SQL, DB design, MongoDB, MS SQL Server	
Oracle	
Microsoft Technologies: ASP.NET	
RPA, Automation anywhere	
SharePoint, Visual Studio, SQL Server	
PaaS, AWS Cloud, S3, EC2	
Pivotal Cloud Foundry	
Microsoft Azure	
MicroServices	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: DevOps Assessment, Advisory, Transformation Client: For many client in Financial Services domain Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Sep 2018 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: DevOps Assessment for clients in Banking and Insurance sectors DevOps Advisory and DevOps Architecture for clients in Banking and Insurance DevOps Transformation
Pre-sales Support for DevOps and Agile Projects
COE Lead - Building competency

^ Back to Top

Category: General US Work Status: Need H

Physically Challenged: No

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.